<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-04-08T21:00:17-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">A better me</title><subtitle>I'm a software developer, woodworker and mathematician.  I love to create things. Whether it's digital, physical, or mathematical, I'll give it a try. This is where I record some of those attempts and some  of my thoughts.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">My first builtin</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/construction/woodworking/2019/01/12/build-in.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My first builtin" /><published>2019-01-12T01:45:24-08:00</published><updated>2019-01-12T01:45:24-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/construction/woodworking/2019/01/12/build-in</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/construction/woodworking/2019/01/12/build-in.html">&lt;p&gt;A several months ago, my sister-in-law asked me to design a builtin to go around her fireplace. This is what it looked like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/builtin/before.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;fireplace before&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Up until that point, I’d used &lt;a href=&quot;https://app.sketchup.com/app?hl=en&quot;&gt;SketUp&lt;/a&gt; to design projects. But I had been wanting to learn how to use &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.autodesk.com&quot;&gt;Fusion 360&lt;/a&gt;, so I figured it would be a good project to work on. It has some pretty powerful features. I don’t use nearly half the features it boasts, but the main thing that interests me is its ability to have parametrized (read “variable”) sizes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, this is the design I came up with:
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/builtin/finaldesign.png&quot; alt=&quot;final design&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I built it such that everything is positioned relative to the fireplace in the middle. That means that I can change the number used for the width of the fireplace and everything else repositions automatically.
For example, here it is if I tell it to use a 96 inch wide fireplace:
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/builtin/widedesign.png&quot; alt=&quot;wide design&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the fireplace is unlikely to change in sizes, but there are several other parameters. For example the gaps between the vertical pieces and the edge of the boxes can all be changed by updating one value in the file. I can also resize any of the boxes and the positions of the other things around it update to fit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This feature was very useful in the design process. For starters I didn’t need to concern myeslf with how large everything should be. I could just pick a number that felt ok enough and make it so that it could be easily updated later. Then I could either show it to Lori or send a picture to her sister and ask what things needed to be updated. It was also helpful as things definitely changed during the week that I built it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For what it’s worth here are some progress shots of the actual work:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/builtin/first.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;first&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/builtin/second.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;second&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/builtin/third.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;third&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s how I left it. It was only a few days and I didn’t have enough time to make doors or paint it. Joni and Greg ended up taking care of that.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/builtin/done.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;done&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">A several months ago, my sister-in-law asked me to design a builtin to go around her fireplace. This is what it looked like:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A better me</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/introduction/2018/12/01/first-post.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A better me" /><published>2018-12-01T01:45:24-08:00</published><updated>2018-12-01T01:45:24-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/introduction/2018/12/01/first-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/introduction/2018/12/01/first-post.html">&lt;p&gt;I want to do more with my life than the 40 hour grind followed by Netflix and chill. I want to always be learning. To teach myself new skills. I want to know and understand more things. To be able to look back and see that I’ve made progress toward these goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To that end I will use this medium to document my projects. Maybe I’ll build something new in the garage, maybe I’ll write a new program, or maybe I’ll teach myself a new subject. (Probably, I’m doing all three at once). Along the way, I’ll document the process and discuss what I learned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keeping things documented will help me stay motivated to finish projects, but it will also provide a place I can look back and remind myself that I have been growing along the way. Along the way if I inspire someone to learn and grow then that’ll be great!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I want to do more with my life than the 40 hour grind followed by Netflix and chill. I want to always be learning. To teach myself new skills. I want to know and understand more things. To be able to look back and see that I’ve made progress toward these goals.</summary></entry></feed>